# Renan Nunes Zerino

Natal/RN | +55 (84) 98888-3690 | renannunescbt@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/renannunesz/

### **About**

Graduated in Systems Analysis and Development, with more than 5 years of experience as an IT Manager, developing projects and managing the implementation of technological solutions to optimize and improve processes. Knowledge in WEB development (HTML, PHP, CSS, JavaScript, XAMP/WAMP), experience with Python, GIT, Visual Basic for Applications, MySql database, Firebird, SQL, and assembly/maintenance of micro computers. Skills with the Power BI data analysis tool (Power Query, DAX) for collecting, processing and visualizing data, generating important analyzes for management.



# **Experiences**

# DATA ANALYST | START BI | 2023

- Carrying out data collection and processing of information.
- Implementing analyses, reports and dashboards with the POWER BI tool.
- Use of DAX language to perform calculations and measurements in the tool.
- Integration of database and excel files for data collection.
- Contact with clients and prospecting, project presentation and negotiation of contracts for data analysis consultancy services.

### IT SUPERVISOR | MÉTODOS CONTABILIDADE EMPRESARIAL | 2019 - 2022

- Promoting control and monitoring of the sector's tasks, as well as implementing new controls for the company's management, in terms of internal controls and indicators.
- Developing new tools to optimize sector performance.
- Monitoring the implementation of acquired tools and being responsible for the implementation project.

# IT ASSISTANT | MÉTODOS CONTABILIDADE EMPRESARIAL | 2016 - 2019

- Promoting integration of information between software and internal and external customers, as well as monitoring service requests relating to the sector.
- Researching, developing and implementing new tools relevant to the area.
- Identified and resolved any hardware problems.

# SERVICE AND IMPLEMENTATION CONSULTANT | M&M INFORMÁTICA (FORTES INFORMÁTICA) | 2009 – 2016

- Developing customer service and telephone support activities, as well as training customers to use the system in the areas of Accounting, Personnel, Tax and Electronic Point control system.
- Developing and participating in collective training on topics that involve the obligations of the departments mentioned in the implementation of system modules.

### **Academic Education**

### SYSTEMS ANALYST | 2020 - 2023 | UNP - UNIVERSIDADE POTIGUAR

Graduation: CST IN ANALYSIS AND SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT

# **Certifications**

DATA ANALYST - MICROSOFT ESCOLA DO WORKER 4.0 DATA ANALYST - MICROSOFT ESCOLA DO WORKER 4.0 - MINISTRY OF LABOR AND EMPLOYMENT

WEB PROGRAMMING - METRÓPOLE DIGITAL - IMD/UFRN

PROGRAMMING IN EXCEL 2013 WITH VBA - SINTEC - SINICATO DOS TECNICOS INDUSTRIAIS DO RN

POWER BI EXPERT IN PRACTICEPOWER BI EXPERT IN PRACTICE - VISCARI INC.

**EXCEL EXPERT - XPERIUN** 

**ADVANCED DATA MODELING - XPERIUN** 

# **Additional Information**

- AB license;
- Available for relocation;
- Knowledge in Networks;
- Assembly and maintenance of computers;
- Native Portuguese;
- English B1